Guide to the Anson Phelps Stokes Autograph Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1713-1958; Series I
  - Tyler, Bennet (1783-1858), 1817 December 13 (Box 9, Folder 577)
    Autographed title-page of his Inaugural Address
  - Tyler, John (1742-1823), 1763 June 18 (Box 9, Folder 578)
    Composition dated
  - Tyler, Moses Coit (1835-1900), 1878 May 22 (Box 9, Folder 579)
    ALS to Prof. Edward E. Salisbury [Transferred to Salisbury Family Papers]
  - Ullmann, Daniel (1810-1892), 1838 September 28 (Box 9, Folder 580)
  - Upham, Thomas Cogswell (1799-1872), 1860 May 21 (Box 9, Folder 581)
    ALS to Mr. Bragonier
  - Van Buren, John (1810-1866), 1859 June 4 (Box 9, Folder 582)
    ALS to Mr. Tyler
  - Van Buren, William Holme (1819-1888), 1873 December 2 (Box 9, Folder 583)
    ALS to E.D. Smith
  - Vanderbilt, Cornelius (1843-1899), 1894 February 1 (Box 9, Folder 584)
    ALS to Bishop Doane
  - VanRensselaer, Cortlandt (1808-1860), 1851 March 28 (Box 9, Folder 585)
    ALS to Dr. Murray
  - VanRensselaer, Jacob Rutsen (1767-1835), 1822 May 14 (Box 9, Folder 586)
    ALS to Alexander W. Muir
  - VanName, Addison (1832-1922), 1877 December 1 (Box 9, Folder 587)
  - Vincent, George Edgar (1864-1941), 1907 December 12 (Box 9, Folder 588)
  - Vinton, Alexander Hamilton (1807-1881), 1880 May 19 (Box 9, Folder 589)
    ALS to A.C. Feuety
  - Wadsworth, James (1730-1817), 1783 December 2 (Box 9, Folder 590)
    ALS to his brother John
  - Wadsworth, James Sr. (b. ca. 1700), 1746 July 1 (Box 9, Folder 591)
    ALS to his son James
  - Wadsworth, James (1768-1844), 1823 August 30 (Box 9, Folder 592)
    MS Letter signed to Secretary of State
  - Wadsworth, James Samuel (1807-1864), 1862 August 14 (Box 9, Folder 593)
    ALS to "His Excellence the Governor"
  - Wadsworth, James Wolcott (1877-1952), 1914 November 27 (Box 9, Folder 594)
  - Waite, Henry Matson (1787-1869), 1833 April 6 (Box 9, Folder 595)
    Summons signed; also portrait
  - Waite, Morrison Remick (1816-1888), 1878 October 25, 1865 October 21 (Box 9, Folder 596)
    ALS to Leonard A. Morrison
    Autograph note to Pres. Woolsey [Transferred to Woolsey Family Papers]
  - Wakeman, Thaddeus Burr (1778-1848), 1836 May 12 (Box 9, Folder 597)
  - Waldo, Daniel (1762-1864), 1856 July 27, 1804 July 4 (Box 9, Folder 598)
    MS Sermon preached at Wash, D.C.
    (and neg. photostat copy)
    MS Sermon delivered
  - Wales, John (1783-1863), 1852 December 20 (Box 9, Folder 599)
    ALS to A.A. Meyer; also portrait
  - Walker, Williston (1860-1922), 1911 December 11 (Box 9, Folder 600)
  - Wang, Chin Chun (1883-1956), 1913 October 8 (Box 9, Folder 601)
  - Washburn, Henry Lucius (1847-1920), 1867 June 19 (Box 9, Folder 602)
  - Watrous, George Dutton (1858-1840), 1908 April 21 (Box 9, Folder 603)
    Signed postcard
  - Webster, Pelatiah (1726-1795), 1747 May 14 (Box 9, Folder 604)
    ALS to Ezra Stiles
    Reproduction of Title page of
    one of his works
    Newspaper clipping
  - Webster, Noah (1758-1843), 1788 August 31 (Box 9, Folder 605)
    ALS to Mr. Babcock
    MS note and biog. note
  - Weeks, Robert Kelley (1840-1876), 1871 December 16 (Box 9, Folder 606)
    ALS to F.B. Dexter
  - Weir, John Ferguson (1841-1926), 1913? October 5 (Box 9, Folder 607)
  - Welch, Pierce Noble (1841-1909), 1907 December 26 (Box 9, Folder 608)
  - Welch, William Wickham (1818-1892), 1856 September 18 (Box 9, Folder 609)
    ALS to George A. Bailey
  - Welles, Noah (1718-1776), 1773 May 17 (Box 9, Folder 610)
    ALS to Messrs. Carpenter and Townsend (separate envelope)
  - West, Stephen (1735-1819), 1802 January 2 (Box 9, Folder 611)
    ALS to Samuel Hopkins
  - Wetmore, George Peabody (1846-1921), 1910 February 10 (Box 9, Folder 612)
  - Wetmore, Izrahiah (1728-1798), 1760 January 6 (Box 9, Folder 613)
    MS Sermon on Titus 2.15
  - Wharton, Francis (1820-1889), 1822 July 12 (Box 9, Folder 614)
    ALS to Prof. R.E. Thompson
  - Wheeler, A.W., 1908 April 23 (Box 9, Folder 615)
    Signed postcard postmarked
  - Wheelock, Eleazar (1711-1779), 1787 June 8, 1773 February 7 (Box 9, Folder 616)
    ALS to Levi Hart
    ALS to Rev. Joseph Strong
  - White, Andrew Dickson (1832-1918), 1870 March 7, 1903 July 25 (Box 9, Folder 617)
    ALS to ____ a recommendation for R. W. Daniels
  - Whitehead, Cortlandt (1842-1922), 1890 November 29 (Box 9, Folder 618)
    ALS to Leighton Coleman
  - Whiting, John (1722-1786), 1760 May 26 (Box 9, Folder 619)
    Deed signed before Judge Whiting
  - Whitney, Eli (1765-1825), 1799 January 8, 1809 February 16 (Box 9, Folder 620)
    ALS to Josiah Whitney
    ALS to Jonathan Sturges
  - Whitney, Josiah Dwight (1819-1896), 1872 December 9 (Box 9, Folder 621)
  - Whitney, William Collins (1841-1904), 1879 September 15 (Box 9, Folder 622)
    ALS to (Thurlow) Weed; also biographical notes
  - Whitney, William Dwight (1827.1894), 1877 March 19 (Box 9, Folder 623)
    ALS to Franklin B. Dexter
    ALS to Edward E. Salisbury [Transferred to Salisbury Family Papers]
  - Whittelsey, Rev. Chauncey (1717-1787), 1775 August 2 (Box 10, Folder 624)
    MS Sermon: bears inscription New Haven Lecture
  - Wilder, Horace (1802-1889), 1841 May 22 (Box 10, Folder 625)
    ALS to Messrs. Bolton and Kelly
  - Williams, Alpheus Starkey (1810-1878), 1865 December 11 (Box 10, Folder 626)
    ALS to Adjutant Gen. U.S.A.
  - Williams, Elisha (1694-1755), 1736 November 9 (Box 10, Folder 627)
  - Williams, Frederick Wells (1857-1928), 1897 December 13 (Box 10, Folder 628)
  - Williams, Samuel Porter (1779-1826), 1817 June (Box 10, Folder 629)
    MS Sermon on I Kings 19.9 with list of places preached
  - Williams, Samuel Wells (1812-1884), 1859 January 27, 1883 November 19 (Box 10, Folder 630)
    ALS to Mr. Reed
    ALS to Peter Parker
  - Williams, Thomas Scott (1777-1861), 1853 March 8 (Box 10, Folder 631)
    ALS to B.W. Williams
  - Williams, Warham (1726-1788), 1745 August 5 (Box 10, Folder 632)
    ALS to "Dear Cousin"
  - Willis, Nathaniel Parker (1806-1867), 1850 August 5 (Box 10, Folder 633)
    ALS to Samuel Ruggles; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Willis, Richard Storrs (1819-1900), 1889 June 19 (Box 10, Folder 634)
    ALS to Hubert P. Main
  - Wilmer, Rt. Rev. Richard Hooker (1816-1900), 1866 June 6 (Box 10, Folder 635)
    ALS to T.B. Tyler; also newspaper picture
  - Wines, Enoch Cobb (1806-1879), 1857 February 5 (Box 10, Folder 636)
    ALS to Rev. Dr. Mathews
  - Winthrop, Theodore (1828-1861), 1851 February 19 (Box 10, Folder 637)
    ALS to "My Dear Uncle" (T. D. Woolsey) [Transferred to Woolsey Family Papers]
  - Wolcott, Oliver (1726-1797), 1763 Jan, 1767 May 9 (Box 10, Folder 638)
    ADS: Bill to T. Seymour
    Account book of O. Wolcott dated
  - Wolcott, Oliver (1760-1833), 1825 March 25 (Box 10, Folder 639)
    ALS to Jeremiah Day
  - Woodford, Stewart Lyndon (1835-1913), 1869 May 24 (Box 10, Folder 640)
    ALS to Horace Greeley; also biographical notes
  - Woods, Leonard (1807-1878), 1869 December 28 (Box 10, Folder 641)
    ALS to "My Dear. Sir"
    also autograph attached to envelope addressed to Mr. Woods
  - Woods, William Burnham (1824-1887) (Box 10, Folder 642)
  - Woolsey, Theodore Dwight ( 1801-1889), 1842 April 11, 1850 July 27, 1866 May 20 (Box 10, Folder 643)
    ALS to J. Munro and Co. (neg. photostat) [Transferred to Woolsey Family Papers]
    Page of Yale Commemoration Address [Transferred to Woolsey Family Papers]
    ALS to Prof. Rockwell [Transferred to Woolsey Family Papers]
    also biographical notes 2 pamphlets and portrait
  - Wooster, David (1710-1777), 1775 April 19, 1775 August 27 (Box 10, Folder 644)
    Statement of Wooster and 2 others as auditors
    ALS to Jonathan Fitch
  - Wooster, William Burr (1821-1900), 1885 February 9 (Box 10, Folder 645)
    ALS to J.B. Bachelder
  - Worcestor, Joseph Emerson (1784-1865), 1855 September 26 (Box 10, Folder 646)
    ALS to Richard Fletcher
  - Worthington, John (1719-1800), 1787 March 5 (Box 10, Folder 647)
    ALS to Gen. Lincoln
  - Wright, Elizur (1804-1885), 1851 September 27, 1852 September 27 (Box 10, Folder 648)
    ALS to Horace Greeley
    ALS to W.L. Crandall and others
  - Wright, Henry Parks (1839-1918), 1912 December 4 (Box 10, Folder 649)
  - Wright, Luther (1796-1870), 1846 August 11 (Box 10, Folder 650)
    ALS to unidentified recipient, being a recommendation for J. S. Newton
  - Wyllys, John Palsgrave (1754-1790), 1782 April 25 (Box 10, Folder 651)
    Inspection return for Third Connecticut
    Regiment diagram in his hand and signed
    Biographical notes
  - Wyllys, Samuel (1739-1823), 1781 February 21, 1759 (Box 10, Folder 652)
    ADS Resolution of the General Assembly of Connecticut regarding the troop quotas (also negative photostat)
    ALS to Silas Deane endorsed
  - Yamakawa, Kenjirō (Box 10, Folder 653)
  - Yates, Andrew (1772-1844), 1820 July 12 (Box 10, Folder 654)
    ALS to Abraham Ten Eyck; biographical notes
  - Young, Ebenezer (1783-1851), 1832 June 11 (Box 10, Folder 655)
    ALS to Mr. Blair editor of the Globe